In this video, I'll show you how to sell
more books on Amazon KDP using free
strategies. So, if you're just starting
out and you don't have a budget for paid
ads, these are effective strategies you
can do right now to increase your sales.
Now, if you're new to the channel, my
name is Shawn. I've been self-publishing
for a very long time. I became a
self-made millionaire from actually
doing Amazon KDP before I started
teaching it on YouTube. So, essentially,
I made all that money just from doing
the business. I am still working on my
own Amazon KDP account to this day. So,
if you want no-BS publishing advice from
someone who's actually doing it, then
make sure to subscribe. So, marketing is
all about getting eyeballs to your book.
If no one knows or sees your book, you
won't make any sales. When you run paid
ads like Amazon ads, you're literally
paying Amazon to put your book in front
of a lot of people. So, you're paying to
get a lot more eyeballs, and that'll
directly translate to sales. Now, I
personally think running ads, especially
Amazon ads, is the most direct and
fastest way to start getting more sales.
However, I do understand that if you're
just getting started, you might not have
the budget for it. Typically, the budget
required is a lot cheaper than you
think. A lot of people somehow think you
got to, you know, have thousands of
dollars to spend on Amazon ads when
you're just getting started. When the
reality is, you really just need couple
bucks a day, right? Like three to five
bucks a day is all you need to start
testing ads, and once you're making more
than you spend, then you start spending
more because you're obviously going to
make more back, right? So, that's how
ads work. But, if you don't even have
three to five bucks a day, or you really
hate ads, you just want to do everything
for free, whatever the reason that is,
this is how you can sell more books
without paid ads. Now, if you watch, you
know, other videos on YouTube, people
will tell you a lot of different things,
right? Do podcast appearance, start
writing on Substack, start blogging by
creating a website and a blog. People
will tell you all kinds of things, but
most of those are basically useless.
It's a complete waste of time. I'm all
about being efficient and shortcutting
my path to making money as much as
possible. So, if you're going to do free
marketing methods, the most direct and
the fastest path to make money doing
that is social media marketing,
specifically posting short-form content.
And that could be on TikTok, that could
be on YouTube, on Instagram, but in
general, TikTok is the most effective by
far. Once again, even with social media
marketing, most likely it's going to
take longer than if you just, you know,
ran paid ads. But that's a trade-off,
right? You're saving money by investing
a lot more time creating these
short-form content, posting it. It's
going to be work, but it's going to be
free for you, right? Or would you rather
save time and just pay money to run ads,
which will save you a lot of time, but
you're, you know, investing money. So,
which do you want, right? You have to
decide that yourself. You know, the
answer, honestly, if you want to really
scale your business to big levels, doing
both is the answer because social media
marketing is amazing, ads is amazing.
So, doing both is the end goal, but if
you have to start with one, that is your
choice. But in terms of social media
marketing, how do you exactly do it?
Well, let me show you some real examples
here. So, this is Mindful Minds
Co-publishing. He is Ashley one of our
coaches in the Road to Hero program. So,
if you do join Road to Hero, you might,
you know, interact with him. But
Jonathan over here is a TikTok expert.
He makes a lot of money from TikTok. A
couple things I want to point out here
is that Jonathan makes tens of thousands
of dollars a month selling these books
on Amazon, but also on TikTok Shop,
which is another platform you can sell
on. However, if you look at the average
views that he's getting, it's just a
couple hundred views per video for the
most part, right? You know, if you sort
by popular here, yes, he does have
videos that's doing, you know, millions
of views, right? Definitely boosted a
lot of sales. But on average, he's doing
a couple hundred views per video, or
sometimes maybe thousands here, right?
So, you just never know which video does
well. But he's making tens of thousands
of dollars a month. I think last time I
asked him, he was doing like 40K a month
or something like that. So, that's point
number one is that, you know, most of
your videos probably will not get a lot
of views. So, it's a volume game when it
comes to short-form content. You know,
obviously, once one video does well, you
want to kind of repeat the formula as
much as possible, but you just want to
keep testing new things and keep posting
multiple videos every single day. The
next point I want to make is that
although Jonathan has videos where he's
showing his face like this, most videos
that went viral are ones where he's not
even showing his face. It's simply
showing the book cover, showing the
interior, you know, with a cool
background music, some text, 4.7 million
views. Got a lot of sales doing this,
right? The second highest viewed, I
think. It's not the second highest, but
this is almost a million views. Same
thing.
Just a simple bureau of the sky going
into the book cover, almost 1 million
views. This one over here, exact same
one. I think what happened is this video
worked well, so he just recreated it and
it worked well again, right? So, it's
just sky bureau going into probably the
book once again.
Yep, same thing with the text. 1 million
views, right? Got a lot of sales. So,
the video itself is not that hard to
create, but obviously, you got to show
up every day. You got to take these
videos, right? And you have to post it
every day, you know, although you can
schedule these. So, that is work and
that's the trade-off compared paid ads,
but you don't have to show your face.
You don't have to do these crazy videos,
you know, simple is best. And this is
actually what you want to do is once you
have a video that's working, you want to
keep repurposing it more and more and
more, right? Keep recreating similar
ones. So, if you sort by popular over
here, most of Jonathan's viral videos
are ones where he's sitting down filming
himself with a book cover showing, you
know, cleverly in the corner over here
with a text. I think this is like a
10-20 second bureau. That is it, right?
And it worked well, so he made multiple
versions of it like more than, what is
this, like more than 10, I think,
overall. And many of them did really
well. He has multiple sky versions over
here. He has multiple showing the book
interior versions over here. So, every
single one of these videos are extremely
simple to create, right? And inside Road
to Hero, I actually have a whole Tik Tok
module where I show you how to come up
with these text, you know, in the
captions with AI super quickly,
unlimited ideas with AI, how to film it,
you know, how to do the research,
essentially everything you need to know
here. But the basic concept is you post
a lot of content, you test out what
works, and then once you find what
works, then you go and try to recreate
it as much as possible, and you still
test new ideas. So, let's say you're not
in a non-fiction, you know, book niche,
and you're in coloring books as an
example. Well, what you want to do is to
find other brands in the coloring book
space and just model what they're doing.
So, this is Coco Real, probably the most
successful publishing brand at the
moment, and these are the videos that
they post, right? So, essentially, the
ones that work are the ones where
they're just coloring, you know, the
pages here and showcase the interior of
their book. Now, this takes a lot more
work because you obviously have to color
it in, make these videos. I got students
in the coloring book space that
outsource this entire process, so they
hire someone that can, you know, color
it in, bought these Ohuhu markers, sent
it to the illustrator, and they filmed
these videos, and my students post it on
their account. So, it is definitely
possible to outsource, but that's going
to cost money, and you know, we're
talking about free marketing strategies.
So, if you want to do coloring books,
you probably have to do it yourself, but
not every single video has to be like
this, right? Colored in. You can always
just do a flip through video or
something a lot simpler, too. But what I
want to show you here is the fact that
they're doing Tik Tok. Yes, Tik Tok is
the first place that you should, you
know, definitely focus on, but you can
repurpose the same videos on Instagram,
and they get less views, I think. I'm
not sure, but typically with Instagram
you get less views than Tik Tok, you
know, from my experience, from
Jonathan's experience, from, you know,
our students' experience, right? But you
still get something, so you still can
pick up some sales there, and you can
repurpose it on YouTube as well, which
you can see here. And for some reason
Coco Real does really well on YouTube.
So, if you're doing coloring books,
maybe YouTube works as well, but that is
another way to pick up even more sales.
So, their social media marketing
strategy is crazy. They have a whole
team, you know, it's a lot of work for
them, but if you can make it work, you
can make a lot of sales. By the way, I
just want to say that I'm not hating on
social media marketing. Clearly, I
believe in social media marketing
because I'm here posting YouTube content
every single week, right? I am going
heavy on YouTube long-form content
because it works, you know, it's working
really well for me. So, social media
works, but when it comes to publishing
books on Amazon, it really depends on
what you want to do. Like, if you're
watching this video right now, and if
you want to do the same thing but for
your books, which means making videos
constantly every single week like how
I'm doing with my YouTube videos, right?
Although I'm promoting a different
product. Again, you're going to be doing
the same thing. So, if you want to do
that, if you're cool with doing that,
investing a lot of time, then social
media marketing is amazing. But, if you
don't want to invest that, as is
available. So, again, it's a trade-off.
But, once again, inside Road to Hero, we
do show you the most efficient way to
create simple videos that converts with
the help of AI. So, if you're interested
in learning more about Road to Hero
because we cover both paid ads and
organic marketing like this, you can
check out the first link in the
description. But, that is how you can
repurpose your content in different
platforms, TikTok, Instagram, YouTube,
very effective. So, now I want to show
you different types of videos you can
create just to give you more ideas. You
know, essentially, there are unlimited
ideas and different videos you can
create, but the best thing you can do is
to find videos that are getting a lot of
views in your niche. So, find other
TikTok pages that are doing well
promoting a book similar to yours. And
you just basically model those videos.
Don't just rip it off, but you know,
make something similar because if it's
working for them, it must work for you,
too. So, the first video type, I call
this the ASMR style because you're not
talking, right? It's very calming,
essentially just a background music with
a text with, you know, book cover
showcase. Here, you can film yourself or
you can just be behind the camera
showing the book, but as you can see,
like 30 seconds of this, okay? So, that
is one style. The next video type is
just a simple talking head video like
how I'm doing with this YouTube video.
But, you know, talking about a topic and
then you pitch a book, right? This
author right here, it might not be
showing in this video, but he does have
a book on I think it's a spiritual
topic, right? Inner work. And he usually
pitches that in the video after talking
about, you know, one concept inside the
book. The next one is just simply
showing your book cover or your book
interiors. I call this a book showcase
videos. But, this is by far my favorite
from all the analyzing, you know, TikTok
videos that I've seen, this video type
performs the best. Literally just
showing your book behind the camera. And
for whatever reason, it converts really
well. So, this one, as we know, Mom and
Dad, I want to hear your story, you
know, it blew up couple years back,
still doing extremely well. Jeffrey, you
know, the the author is a legend over
here, right? And it's just a simple
showing the book cover, talking about
it, you know, and that is it. 10 million
views, crazy stuff. The next one is also
from here your story, and this is the
book flipping or the, you know, the
interior showing. And this also is my
favorite, right? So, you know, showing
the book cover, showing the interior,
maybe a combination of both. The easiest
video to create, as you can see, no
editing, nothing. You just turn on the
camera, start flipping, and you talk
about it. You're not even doing the
exercises, right? You're just, you know,
going over each prompts here. And this
video got, I believe, millions of views,
and I'm sure it generated a lot of
sales. This is also a good one. This is
just reading one page. So, you know,
this is a crazy part, right? You can
flip through the entire book, show the
entire pages, but the next video you can
just work on one page, right? And one
page is one video. And she's not even
doing the exercises, she's just like
literally reading the text out loud and
going over. And this video got 70
million views. 70 million views. Imagine
the amount of sales it generated, right?
And this is from the Shadow Work
Journal. It was the number one
best-selling book, I think, 3 years ago,
4 years ago, I forgot. So, it definitely
does work. And by the way, if you got a
100-page book, one page is one video.
That means you can create 100 videos
from one book. And the thing is, with
social media, you can make similar
videos over and over and over. So, once
you go, you know, make those 100 videos,
you can just start over from page one
and just start making, you know, 100
videos from start again. So, you
essentially got unlimited content. Next
one is the coloring page book. We've
seen this already, but it's just
coloring in the page that you have
inside. It's a little bit more work, but
it looks really nice and it performs
really well. So, as you can see, you
know, these videos aren't that hard to
create. You can just order a book, you
know, and you can just flip through it,
show the book cover, you know, there are
a lot of simple video ideas to create.
But, for whatever reason, if you really,
really don't want to show yourself, show
the book, have everything purely done
online with perhaps using AI, then these
are some AI TikTok examples, okay? So,
this is a carousel video. So, it's a
auto scrolling video different images
over here, and it is from a children's
book brand, Hayden Fox Media, and it's
simple as 10 responsibilities for your
kid that should take on by age 10.
Personal hygiene, Midjourney generated
image with a text, AI generated image
with a text, and basically 10 of those,
right? And it goes all the way until the
end. And maybe it has a call to action
over here. Now, the call to action is
just to, you know, comment. But, you see
the amount of saves and engagement.
Like, isn't that crazy? 34,000 saves.
And he has a link in the bio, so, you
know, gets a lot of sales spillover from
there. All right, so hopefully that gave
you some ideas on how you can get
started with social media marketing,
which is by far the most effective free
marketing strategy to start selling your
book. By the way, if you're wondering,
how can you go from TikTok to, you know,
selling books on Amazon? Well, if you go
viral on social media, people will
automatically look up the book on
Amazon, so you get a lot of spillovers
without ever mentioning that the book is
on Amazon. I've seen this happen
multiple times, so that definitely
happens. But once you have enough
followers, you can do a link in bio and
link to Amazon, or you can create your
own website and you can, you know, link
to Amazon from there. However way you
want to do it, you can definitely do it.
You can also sell your books on TikTok
Shop, which is a more advanced strategy
and it's definitely not free. But if you
start getting good at social media
marketing and you have proven video
templates that every time you make a
video like this, you know, you're
getting a lot of views, and if you get
consistent views from social media
marketing, your next move definitely
should be TikTok Shop because you can
make a lot of money from TikTok Shop.
And TikTok Shop and Amazon KDP goes hand
in hand, it goes really well together.
So, if you're curious about how that
works, I do have this video right here
on TikTok Shop for Amazon KDP. We'll put
it up somewhere on the screen, so you
can go and watch that video next. Now,
if you do want to work with us, work
with me and my team of coaches,
including Jonathan, as you saw earlier
here, and have us help you implement the
Road to Hero method into your publishing
business, which has a track record of
scaling people to four, five, or even
six figures per month and has over 520
Trustpilot reviews with over 4.9 average
rating, then you can go to the first
link in the description below. There's a
short video that you can watch on how
this works, and if everything sounds
good, you can book a call. It's a free
30-minute strategy session, you talk to
one of our coaches, not sales reps, and
we can basically see if this program is
a fit for you. We don't accept everybody
because this is a coaching program, we
work very closely with you, which means
it takes a lot of time from us as well.
So, we don't just accept everyone
because we want to make sure that we can
actually help you and also, you know,
you are a coachable person, right? We
don't work with someone who's a probably
going to be a headache and not the best
attitude. I also want to, you know, give
a very clear disclaimer that this is not
a get-rich-quick scheme. Amazon KDP is a
real business, we have a lot of success
stories, you know, inside our program,
but obviously results aren't guaranteed.
It'll take a lot of work and commitment
from your side, but if you're willing to
put in the work, I generally believe
that this is the best coaching program
out there. So, with that being said,
thank you so much for watching. If you
enjoyed the video, leave a like,
subscribe, and I'll see you guys in the
next one.